HONG JIA HERNG

Penang | Malaysia

+60187735033 | jiaherng2001@gmail.com

LinkedIn | linkedin.com/in/jia-herng-hong-7206461b6

GitHub | github.com/hongjiaherng

ABOUT

I am a second-year undergraduate computer science student at University of Malaya. I enjoy learning machine learning in my free time which includes the underlying theory and programming frameworks. I am interested in pursuing a job related to machine learning research later in my career.

EDUCATION

University of Malaya (Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia)

Bachelor of Computer Science (Information Systems)

Oct 2020 – Apr 2024 CGPA: 3.95/4.00

EXPERIENCES

University of Malaya (Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia)

Aug 2021 - Oct 2021

- Research Assistant
 - Assisted in conducting research on image steganography method using GANbased model
 - Wrote scripts to exploit secret-embedded images using clustering algorithms (e.g., k-means, spectral, agglomerative, DBSCAN, etc.) and measure its performance using clustering evaluation metrics
 - Analyzed data produced by clustering to improve the proposed method in terms of difficulty to be attacked by malicious party
 - O Developed methods to improve the look and feel of secret-embedded image

Google Developer Student Club UM

Sept 2021 - Present

- Tech Lead / Machine Learning Division Lead
 - Organized a 4-session workshop called 'Head Start Machine Learning' to teach fundamental concepts and programming libraries in machine learning using Python
 - Taught the basic concepts using Linear Regression (e.g., common notations, model hypothesis, gradient descent, etc.) and ML project workflow
- Machine Learning Division Member

Oct 2020 - Jun 2021

PROJECTS

Runtimeterror

A food ingredients distributor system created to automate the process of ordering with data scrubbing. A project created for Dell Hack2Hire competition. (Tools: Django, ReactJS, Firestore, Pandas)

ML-Collection

Personal repository for keeping my own-implemented ML algorithms while learning. Code in Python with the support of NumPy and several Python scientific computing's libraries.

Sentuh dan Lari

A Software Modelling class's project to model an improved Touch 'n Go eWallet using UML diagramming software.

Sociopath

A friendship simulating application to demonstrate graph data structure and several algorithms. Created using Java with JavaFX, styled with CSS, and Neo4j for storing people's data.

iHeallth

A desktop app for patients to reserve and book appointment time in a clinic. Created using Java with JavaFX, styled with CSS, and MongoDB for storing patients' data.

SKILLS

Developer Tools

- Python (NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, TensorFlow, Scikit- HTML, CSS (SASS) learn, Django)
- Java (JavaFX, Swing)
- SQL, MySQL, Oracle DB, MongoDB, Neo4j
- MATLAB
- SPSS
- R
- UML

Others

Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, Premiere Pro

Languages

- Chinese, native
- English, working proficiency (MUET Band 4)
- Malay, working proficiency

AWARDS

- Dell Hack2Hire 2022 Special Mentioned Team (Runtime Terror)
- Penang Future Foundation 2020 Penang Scholar's scholarship recipient
- Programming League 2021 4th place (closed category)
- King Scout Award 2018